# DIEGO SÁNCHEZ MARTÍN

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

#### SKILLS

#### Programming languages:

Python, Java, C++, C#, JavaScript, TypeScript, C, XAML, Swift.

#### Tools:

Docker, Jira, Node.Js, Hibernate, Java Persistance API (JPA), REST APIs, PowerBI, Grafana reporting, Atlassian.

#### **Web Frameworks**

React.JS, Vue.JS. SpringBoot, Qt Framework and QML.

#### Databases:

FireBase, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MariaDB.

#### Repositories:

Git, Github, Gitlab, Continuous Integration (CI) and continuous Delivery (CD)

#### Testing:

Cypress.io, Pytest, Cucumber.io, Junit, Mockito, Selenium, Jenkins, React Testing Library, Appium, TestRail,Test Management, Test Development.

#### Methodologies:

Agile, Scrum.

#### Others:

Knowledge of development in unity and unreal engine 4, bash and shell scripting, HTML, CSS.

#### **ABOUT ME**

Currently, I work as a Senior QA at WOCU Monitoring, a company dedicated to the development of monitoring solutions for the industry. There, I am in charge of designing, developing and executing end-to-end tests with Cypress, integrating this tool with Gitlab CI to automate test execution. I also configure and maintain a docker instance for test execution. Previously, I worked at HP SCDS, where I automated product firmware testing with Python and software simulation tools. My experience has allowed me to gain skills in programming languages such as Java, Python and C++, as well as mobile and web application development. As a professional, I am committed to continuous learning and adoption of new technologies.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE**

SPECIAL MENTION IN INFORMATION TECHNOLOGIES

University of Salamanca USAL | 2018 - 2022 (Graduated)

• Specialization in computer science (Programming Languages, Parallelism, Artificial Intelligence, Robotics, Databases, Process Control, Operating Systems, Computer Networks, Digital Animation, Computer Security).

#### MASTER'S DEGREE IN ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE (INTELLIGENT SYSTEMS)

University of Salamanca USAL | 2022 - 2024 (Graduated)

o Specialization in Human-computer interaction, Artificial neural networks, Neural networks, Control system design, Multi-agent systems, Artificial intelligence, Data mining, Web mining, Intelligent systems, Data science, Large language models, Information retrieval, Natural Language Processing, Feature Engineering, Data Visualization, Ambient Intelligence, Internet of Things, Industrial Internet of Things (IoT), Deep Learning, Social Media Data Mining, Machine Learning, Feature Selection, Speech Recognition, Generative Al Tools, Generative Al, Generative Artificial Intelligence and Recommendation Systems.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **QA AUTOMATION ENGINEER SENIOR**

WOCU Monitoring | October 2023 to now | Madrid metropolitan area (Remotely), Comunidad de Madrid

- Development of End-to-end (E2E) testing with Cypress.io, JavaScript and Typescript
- Code Review, Continuous Delivery (CD) and Continuous Integration (CI) with GitLab and Git.
- Integrate Cypress with Gitlab CI for tests execution automation
- Manager in the design and prioritization of tests to generate a balanced and automated testing test plan for the software developed in the company.
- Early detection of problems and bugs in development and production roles before the release of a product branch.
- Performing exploratory tests on all products in each new version.
- Record all incidents found in a Ticketing system.
- Configuration and maintenance of docker instance for tests execution.
- Creation and operation of new Linux-based machines for test execution.
- Implementation of package with cypress extension for Google chrome for end-user test management.

## PERSONAL SKILLS

Adaptability
Teamwork
Creativity
Communication
Critical thinking
Problem resolution
Leadership
Organization
Commitment
Curiosity
Attention to detail
Self-learning ability
Assertive
communication

### CONTACT



+34 635834160



sanchhez08@gmail.com



diegosanchezmartin



diegosanchezmartin

## DIEGO SÁNCHEZ MARTÍN

COMPUTER SCIENCE ENGINEER

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **OA AUTOMATION ENGINEER QUALIFIED I**

HP SCDS | June 2023 to October 2023 | Léon metropolitan area (Remotely), Castilla y León

- Development of components with C++.
- Use of the Qt framework for the development of the code.
- Combination of previous tools with the and use of the QML language in the development.
- Development of End-to-end (E2E) testing with Pytest framework and the own testing libraries developed in the company.
- Bug fixes in application components and system tests.
- Acceptance of the quality strategy followed for the development of the components by the developers.
- Review and analysis of the tests developed in the grafana analytical tool

#### **QA AUTOMATION ENGINEER JUNIOR**

HP SCDS | June 2022 - June 2023 | Léon metropolitan area (Remotely), Castilla y León

- Automation of product firmware tests and system tests with Python.
- Linux, Git, GitHub, VSCode and the Pytest framework for development automation with continuous integration.
- Use of software simulation tools such as QEMU in Linux environment.
- Debugging of QT graphical elements of the user interface with the Gammaray tool.
- Quality control of components to be developed.
- Tracking development activities, reviewing and creating user stories, spikes and bugs and issues with Jira and reporting test results with Power BI.
- Follow-up test executions and analysis of the results.
- Agile environment.
- Improves project performance by adding QML code to the elements that developers create
- Participate in team meetings.
- Reviewer of the tests created by different teams and the components that are being developed. Review of epics in Jira to create acceptance criteria and ask if System Tests are required.

#### **INTERNSHIPS**

Qindel Group | February to May 2022 | Léon metropolitan area (Remotely), Castilla y León

- Developing a web development project, contributing knowledge in documentation tasks, programming and acquiring knowledge in different technological environments.
- I have developed the frontend part with Javascript and React, performing unit tests with React Testing Library.
- For the backend part, I have used Java with SpringBoot, a dependency manager like Maven, together with JPA, Hibernate and tools like Postman. Testing has also been done following TDD with Mockito and JUnit.

#### **DEFINITELY**

If you are looking for a person eager to grow at your side, with a promising character, who is capable of carrying out an adequate quality assurance strategy, of detecting your problems effectively and automating your software components to achieve quality extraordinary, do not hesitate to contact me through any of the contact methods indicated below.